A Guide to the 1930-1999
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek McClenahan Papers 1930-1999
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 302
Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek McClenahan
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift to Special Collections and Archives from Mrs. McClenahan in April 1994. Additional materials were added in 1996 and in 2000.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek McClenahan is a Richmond community leader, activist and philanthropist. She has been described as the "conscience of Richmond" for her contributions to the Richmond community in the areas of racial harmony, housing, Richmond revitalization and historic preservation. She has also been active in the arts, her church, and education.
Born in Richmond on April 6, 1917, Mary Tyler is the daughter of Douglas Southall Freeman (1886-1953), noted historian and journalist, and Inez Goddin Freeman (1891-1974). She attended St. Catherine's School and Vassar College, receiving an A.B. in English-Creative Writing in 1937.
After college she worked briefly as a secretary in the Department of Fine Arts of William and Mary College where she met Leslie Cheek, Jr. (1908-1992), then head of the department. They married in 1939. The Cheeks lived in Baltimore for three years while Mr. Cheek was Director of the Baltimore Museum of Fine Arts and in Washington, D.C. during World War II. While Mr. Cheek served in the Army, Mrs. McClenahan volunteered as a nurse's aid. After Cheek's discharge from the Army in 1945, they lived in New York City where Cheek had been hired as an Associate Editor of Architectural Forum Magazine. The couple returned to Richmond when Cheek became the first director of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (1948-1968). The Cheeks had four children. After Mr. Cheek's death in 1992, Mrs. Cheek married Dr. John Lorimer McClenahan, a retired Pennsylvanian radiologist, the following year.
Mrs. McClenahan is responsible for a number of Richmond civic initiatives, including bringing together the 35 groups that make up the Richmond Better Housing Coalition and founding the Richmond Urban Forum. She was twice president of the Virginia League for Planned Parenthood and has participated as a volunteer and board member of numerous Richmond civic organizations, including Richmond Renaissance and Richmond-On- The- James. She has also been an active member of Richmond's historic St. Paul's Episcopal Church.
Some of the organizations Mrs. McClenahan has been associated with include:
Member, Executive Committee and Board of The Arts Council of Richmond
Member, 175th Anniversary of the Executive Mansion Commission
Advisory Committee Girl Scouts
Member, Board of Historic Richmond Foundation
Dame and Member of the Board of Governors of the Most Venerable Order of the Hospital of St. John of Jerusalem
Member, National Committee, Jefferson Poplar Forest Fund
Member, Board of Leadership Metro Richmond
Member, Board of Maymont Foundation
Chairman, Film Committee of the National Council for America's First Freedom: The Virginia Statue for Religious Freedom
Richmond AIDS Ministry
Co-Chairman, Richmond Better Housing Coalition
Member, Board of Richmond Hill
Member, Board of Richmond-On-The-James
Member, Executive Committee and Board of Richmond Renaissance
Founder and Honorary Chairman, Richmond Urban Forum
Director for Virginia and Past President, Robert E. Lee Memorial Association which administers Stratford Hall, the birthplace of Robert E. Lee
Former Vestry member and Junior Warden of St. Paul's Episcopal Church
Member, Board of Theatre Virginia Past President (twice) and honorary board member of Virginia League for Planned Parenthood
Trustee, Virginia Union University
Clubs include:
Cosmopolitan Club, NYC
Hroswitha Club, NYC
James River Garden Club, Richmond
Richmond First Club
Richmond Kiwanis
Virginia Writer's Club
Woman's Club of Richmond
Awards Mrs. McClenahan has received include:
Richmond's Christmas Mother (1973)
Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities' Mary Maso Williams Award (1977)
Junior League of Richmond's Barbara Renson Andrews Award for Distinguished Volunteer Service (1982)
St Catherine's School's Distinguished Alumni Award (1983)
Virginia League of Planned Parenthood Distinguished Service Award (1984)
National Conference of Christian and Jews' Brotherhood Citation (1985)
Omicron Delta Kappa's Conspicuous Attainment Award (1986)
YWCA of Richmond's Outstanding Woman of the Year (1986)
Richmond First Club's Good Government Award (1987)
Richmond Urban League's Charlotte T. Washington Community Services Award (1988)
Style Magazine's Richmonder of the Year (1991)
Housing Opportunities Made Equal (H.O.M.E.) Fair Housing Award
H.O.M.E. Sallie Wilson Peake Memorial Award for Outstanding Support of Fair Housing
National Multiple Sclerosis Society, Silver Hope Award (1994)
Honorary Degrees Mrs. McClenahan has received:
Doctor of Humanities from University of Richmond
Doctor of Humane Letters from St. Paul's College
Doctor of Humane Letters from Washington and Lee University
Doctor of Humane Letters from Hollins College
Doctor of Humane Letters from Virginia Commonwealth University
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes correspondence, notes, clippings, various organizational minutes, reports and files, drafts of speeches, manuscripts and published materials dating from 1933 through 1993. The bulk of the collection dates from the late 1970s through the early 1990s and focuses on Mrs. McClenahan's involvement on issues of race, housing, historic preservation, and Richmond revitalization.
The organizational records in the collection include material from many of Richmond's major civic organizations, including Planned Parenthood, the Richmond Better Housing Coalition, Richmond-On-The-James, Richmond Renaissance and the Richmond Urban Forum. The activities of other organizations are also represented to a lesser degree. A number of these organizations are represented in other collections within Special Collections & Archives. Please ask a staff member for more information.
The collection also contains material documenting Mrs. McClenahan's involvement in education, the arts and politics in Richmond and Virginia, in St. Paul's Episcopal Church, and speeches she has given. Other material in the collection ranges from correspondence of friends and family to material on her daily life, social plans, family holidays and vacations to information on her various interests.
Organization
The collection is divided into a series of eight sections. Series I is primarily correspondence to Mrs. McClenahan. Series II consists of material of twelve major civic and volunteer organizations with which she was involved. Because of the volume of the materials, each organization in this series was divided into its own subseries. Series III is composed of other organizations in which she was active, but of sufficient quantity to justify its own subseries. The material in this series is divided alphabetically. Series IV is a collection of her speeches and articles. The speeches in this series are unidentified by audience or sponsor or affiliated with a group not otherwise not listed in another series. Additional speeches may be found in organizational series by checking folder headings. Series V contains material regarding political candidates and issues. Series VI consists of material relating to the various schools, colleges and universities she has been associated with and is divided alphabetical. Series VII contains material relating to her work with St. Paul's Episcopal Church. Series VIII consists of a variety of material reflecting Mrs. McClenahan's daily activities, social plans, and wide range of interests. [See the NOTE under Series for additional materials added in 2000.]
Series I--Correspondence (1933-1993)
Series II--Major volunteer organizations, Subseries A: Arts Council of Richmond (1982-1988), Subseries B: Maymont Foundation (1979-1992), Subseries C: Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce (1981-1992), Subseries D: Planned Parenthood (1942-1992), Subseries E: Richmond Better Housing Coalition (1984-1993), Subseries F: Richmond-On-The-James (1978-1988), Subseries G: Richmond Renaissance (1982-1990), Subseries H: Richmond Urban Forum (1982-1990), Subseries I: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (1957-1993), Subseries J: Virginia Statute for Religious Freedom (1983-1990), Subseries K: Virginia Historical Society (1990-1993), Subseries L: Poplar Forest (1988-1993)
Series III--Other organizations (1951-1993)
Series IV--Speeches and Articles (1955-1993)
Series V--Politics (1985-1993)
Series VI--Schools, Colleges and Universities (1948-1993)
Series VII--St. Pauls' Episcopal Church (1937-1992)
Series VIII--Alphabetical Files (1935-1993)
Note: Additional materials were added in July 2000. The materials in these containers, boxes 91-109, were added to the end of the collection and are divided as follows: Correspondence (n.d., 1930-1998); Maymont Foundation (n.d., 1983-1997); Richmond Better Housing Coalition (n.d., 1988-1999); Richmond Renaissance (n.d., 1987-1996); miscellaneous colleges and schools (n.d., 1967-1997); Richmond Urban Forum (19- 19); Robert E. Lee Memorial Foundation (1968-1993); St. Paul's Episcopal Church (n.d., 1984-1998); Stratford Hall (n.d., 1984-1989); Virginia Historical Society (n.d., 1983-1992); Virginia Union University (n.d., 1988- 1993); and miscellaneous civic and volunteer organizations (n.d., 1967-1998).
Contents List
- Correspondence 1933-1993
  - Aars, Ferninand and Eva 1956 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Architects Award 1991 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Edwin and Lavane 1956 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Mrs. Anna Bing ( Art & the Art of Living) 1978 (Box 1)
  - Asch, Andrew J. Jr. 1983-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - Ashworth, Mrs. O.O. (associate of D.S. Freeman) n.d. 1990 (Box 1)
  - Ashworth, Sarah 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Bache, Harold L. and Alice n.d. 1968 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Betty Scott 1980 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Bill n.d. 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Helen S. (Portrait of D.S. Freeman) 1990 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Julia 1945 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Herbert 1980 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, C. Hampton 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Waller and Coenie 1965 (Box 1)
  - Belin, Mary 1945 (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Craig, III n.d. 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Blanton, Mrs. Wyndham n.d. 1955-1957, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Bocock, Elisabeth n.d. 1955-1984 (Box 1)
  - Boushall, Thomas C. 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Bragg, William Harris 1985, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - Bragg, William Harris Mystery of Lee's Lost Dispatches (Box 1)
  - Bragg, William Harris Our Joint Labor (Box 1)
  - Brainend, Susan M. 1984 (Box 1)
  - Brawley, Frances W. n.d. 1988 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Carter 1978 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, John Stewart 1934-1939 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, John Stewart--Obituary [includes article on Bryan by Douglas Southall Freeman in the Alumni Gazette, College of William and Mary, December 1944, V. 7, n. 2] 1944 (Box 2)
  - Buhl, C. Henry and El 1991 (Box 2)
  - Burke, Mrs. Jackson n.d. 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Cabell, Mrs. Royal E. (Kathleen) 1987 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Rev. Benjamin P. 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Cecil Cary n.d. 1947-1973 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Trial n.d. 1987 (Box 2)
  - Caravati, Charles M. 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Carey, Mrs. Churchill G. (Juliet McAdams) 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - Carter, William A. III 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Al n.d. 1987 (Box 2)
  - Chambuss, R.E. n.d. (Box 2)
  - Cheek, Patsy--Condolences 1988 (Box 2)
  - Cheek, Patsy--Illness, Letters 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1959-1961 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1964, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1966 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1977 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1978 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Cards 1979 (Box 3)
  - Christmas Cards 1986 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Jamie 1956 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Jeanne 1966 (Box 3)
  - Clinton, Marshall 1934 (Box 3)
  - Coats, Peter n.d. 1981 (Box 3)
  - Cochran, Alex and Cally n.d. 1945 (Box 3)
  - Constable, George n.d. (Box 3)
  - Cooperman, Alvin n.d. (Box 3)
  - Corbin, Bessie n.d. 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Cowles, Donald and Jane n.d. (Box 3)
  - Crawford, Sara n.d. (Box 3)
  - Creighton, Virginia H. (Mrs. Thomas C. Creighton) 1945 (Box 3)
  - CSX Corporation 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Daniel, Sally 1980 (Box 3)
  - Darnielle, B. Jackson 1982 (Box 3)
  - Davis, Hester 1955-1959, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Debevoise, Betty n.d. 1984 (Box 3)
  - Decorative Arts Society 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Deep Run Hunt Club 1939 (Box 3)
  - Dickson, Keith n.d. 1982 (Box 3)
  - Dodge, Eleanor (Vassar) 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Doepp, Jack n.d. (Box 3)
  - Dohn, Helen (Mrs. Alfred A. Dohn) 1961 (Box 3)
  - Duggan, Stephen Pierce Mr. and Mrs. 1938 (Box 3)
  - Dunn, R. Keith n.d. (Box 3)
  - Dunn, R. Keith 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Dunn, R. Keith 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Dupont, Mrs. Alfred I. (Miss Jessie) 1958 (Box 3)
  - Dupont, Mrs. Felix 1962 (Box 3)
  - Dwyer, Kathy n.d. 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Edmunds, Mrs. Richard Coles (Pochantas Night) n.d. 1969-1972 (Box 4)
  - Eggers, Mr. and Mrs. Henry Thompson 1945 (Box 4)
  - Ellis, Martha Anne 1989 (Box 4)
  - Eppes, William 1985-1991 (Box 4)
  - Evans, Randy and Lynn 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - Fauntleroy, Elise W. 1951 (Box 4)
  - Ferguson, Frances D. 1990 (Box 4)
  - Freeman, D. 1985 (Box 4)
  - Friday, Mr and Mrs. William (Ida) 1979 (Box 4)
  - Friendly, Pie Pinckney 1987-1989 (Box 4)
  - Fulton, Sally 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Foster, Carmen 1990 (Box 4)
  - Gardner, Joe and Florence n.d. 1968 (Box 4)
  - Garrabrant, Joan n.d. 1989 (Box 4)
  - Garrett, Johnson 1945 (Box 4)
  - Gibson, Alison and Bob 1990 (Box 4)
  - Gibson, George D. 1977-1982 (Box 4)
  - Gignilliat, John 1982-1989 (Box 4)
  - Godwin, Katherine (Mrs. Mills E. Godwin Sr.) n.d. (Box 4)
  - Goetz-Carolyn and Tom 1984 (Box 4)
  - Gold, Mike 1984 (Box 4)
  - Gordon, Paul (Franklin Street Controversy) 1989 (Box 4)
  - Graham, Katharine Meyer n.d. (Box 4)
  - Greene, Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Lee 1944 (Box 4)
  - Grigg, Mr. John 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Haggins, Carl 1989 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Barbara n.d. (Box 4)
  - Hambleton, T. Edward 1980 (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Earl n.d. 1959-1960 (Box 4)
  - Hamilton, Susie n.d. 1981 (Box 4)
  - Harrison, Albertis and Lacey Virginia n.d. 1969 (Box 4)
  - Harwell, Richard B. 1974-1984 (Box 5)
  - Heistand, Hilary n.d. 1961, 1978, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Heistand, R. n.d. (Box 5)
  - Higgins, Ethel K. 1960 (Box 5)
  - Hinnant, Billie (Mrs. Clarence Henry Hinnant, Jr.) 1966 (Box 5)
  - Holt, Molly n.d. 1982 (Box 5)
  - Hotchkiss, Frances (Mrs. Whitewell Forbes Hotchkiss) 1960 (Box 5)
  - Howard, Harold and Nancy 1984 (Box 5)
  - Howe, Thomas Carr 1980 (Box 5)
  - Humelsine, Carlisle and Mary, n.d. 1957,1967 (Box 5)
  - Jeffress, Elizabeth (Mrs. Robert Miller Jefferson) n.d. 1961 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Nessa Baskerville 1980-1983 (Box 5)
  - Jones, Dr. Albert 1989-1991 (Box 5)
  - Kane, Amanda and Keith n.d. 1956-1990 (Box 5)
  - Kelly, Mrs. John (Denver Garden Club) n.d. 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Kirby, James Lewis (order of the Pine, Pig and Peanut) n.d. 1985-1990 (Box 5)
  - Lloyd, Eliza Winn n.d. (Box 6)
  - Magill, Arthur 1982-1984 (Box 6)
  - Manufacturer's Hanover Bank 1987-1991 (Box 6)
  - Marsh, Henry L. III 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Massey, Margaret n.d. 1988 (Box 6)
  - McCarthy, Frank n.d. 1945-1986 (Box 6)
  - McGuire, Dr. Lockhart n.d. 1990-1991 (Box 6)
  - McLendon, Rev. Charles H. Jr. 1984-1986 (Box 6)
  - Meek, Samuel W. 1975-1980 (Box 6)
  - Mielziner, Jo. 1958 (Box 6)
  - Millner, Rev. T. C. n.d. 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence n.d. 1933-1937 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence n.d. 1983 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1991-1993 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Thomas L. 1934-1935 (Box 6)
  - Morrison, Patty and Bill 1965 (Box 6)
  - Morton, David C. 1945 (Box 6)
  - Mowry, Shirrard Willcox Pollard (Mrs. William Mowry Jr.) 1933-1939 (Box 6)
  - Mundy, Ethel Frances 1945 (Box 6)
  - Murphy, Paul 1989 (Box 6)
  - Murrell, Thomas W., M.D. 1960 (Box 6)
  - Nagel, Charles and Lucie n.d. (Box 6)
  - Near, Pickney and Henrietta n.d. 1990 (Box 6)
  - Neblett, Nathaniel Palmer 1984 (Box 6)
  - New Virginia Review 1980 (Box 6)
  - Oenslager, Dona and Zorka n.d. 1969-1975 (Box 6)
  - PACE Magazine 1984 (Box 6)
  - Palmer, Fred 1960 (Box 7)
  - Parkerson, Sen. William F. Jr. 1987 (Box 7)
  - Parks, Jan and Charlotte 1985 (Box 7)
  - Pearson, Mr. and Mrs. Reginald Francis n.d. (Box 7)
  - Plant, Mary and Jim 1959 (Box 7)
  - Pollard, Fred G. (Lt. Gov.) 1966 (Box 7)
  - Popper, Jan and Beta 1976 (Box 7)
  - Randolph E. Fairfax 1984 (Box 7)
  - Rashid, Valorie 1989 (Box 7)
  - Rawles, Elizabeth n.d. 1968 (Box 7)
  - Read, Mrs. Barclay K. 1987 (Box 7)
  - Reed, M.R.S. n.d. 1953 (Box 7)
  - Reed, Mr. and Mrs. William T. 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Remlov, Arne and Lill 1970 (Box 7)
  - Reniers, Ashton 1961 (Box 7)
  - Rhoads, Ravenel n.d. (Box 7)
  - Richmond Quarterly 1978-1990 (Box 7)
  - Roane, Robert N. 1985-1987 (Box 7)
  - Robertson, Harry W. 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Robertson, Mr. and Mrs. Dwight Edwards 1945 (Box 7)
  - Rockefeller, John D., III 1973-1980 (Box 7)
  - Rogers, Debra L. 1984 (Box 7)
  - Scott, Mildred n.d. (Box 7)
  - Smith, C. Kingsley 1969 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Ernest Walker 1935 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Muriel 1985-1986 (Box 7)
  - Sokolow, Anna 1967 (Box 7)
  - Stafford, Betty n.d. (Box 7)
  - Stanley, Gov. and Mrs. Thomas B. n.d. 1956 (Box 7)
  - Stevens, Ruth and David n.d. (Box 7)
  - Stollenwreck, Mary Joe and Stoney 1984 (Box 7)
  - Stoneman, Lenora n.d. (Box 7)
  - Strong, Alice n.d. (Box 7)
  - Style Letters 1991 (Box 7)
  - Style Letters and Replies 1991 (Box 7)
  - Sully, Julia n.d. 1936 (Box 7)
  - Tanners Ridge n.d. 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Taylor, Alec Clifton 1964 (Box 8)
  - Taylor, Mr. and Mrs. Stuart Symington 1945 (Box 8)
  - Thorton, Bill n.d. (Box 8)
  - Timbrel, Mr. and Mrs. Clayton Carey 1945 (Box 8)
  - Times Dispatch Article 1988 (Box 8)
  - Travers, Bernice E. 1986 (Box 8)
  - Turner, Arletla 1961 (Box 8)
  - Turner, Mrs. Lawson (Cele.) n.d. 1965-1973 (Box 8)
  - Valentine, Francis 1958 (Box 8)
  - Van Vleck, Joseph Jr. 1960 (Box 8)
  - Vietoe, Anna Glen and Alec n.d. 1961, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Home 1986 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Magazine of History and Biography 1986 (Box 8)
  - Vocal Line Theatre Company 1991 (Box 8)
  - Von Bulow, Claus n.d. 1975-1989 (Box 8)
  - Wagner, V.H. (Pick) 1935 (Box 8)
  - Walker, Una and Alex n.d. (Box 8)
  - Wallstein, Isabel n.d. (Box 8)
  - Walter, Janet 1936 (Box 8)
  - Ward, Nadine (Richmond News Leader) 1938 (Box 8)
  - Warren, Gwendolin Sims 1985 (Box 8)
  - White, Frances 1980 (Box 8)
  - Whitehouse, Shelden 1965 (Box 8)
  - Wilkinson, Burke n.d. 1973-1977 (Box 8)
  - Willey, Baylies 1982-1985 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Eda 1966 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Mrs. Francis D. (Box 8)
  - Willams, Hazel O. 1986-1988 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Dr. and Mrs. Langbourne 1978 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Maude n.d. (Box 8)
  - Williams, Murat 1989 (Box 8)
  - Winnett, Ralph 1967 (Box 8)
  - Yu, Sau Lan 1961 (Box 8)
- Major Volunteer Organizations 1942-1995
  - Arts Council of Richmond 1982-1988
    - Arts Council of Richmond 1987 (Box 9)
    - Arts Council of Richmond 1988 (Box 9)
    - Adopted School Committee (Woodville Elem.) 1986-1988 (Box 9)
    - Awards 1982 (Box 9)
    - Arts Council of Richmond Bell Ringing Project 1982 (Box 9)
    - Board Retreat 1987 (Box 9)
    - June Jubilee 1986 (Box 9)
    - June Jubilee 1988 (Box 9)
    - Multi-Slide Presentation 1982 (Box 9)
    - Omni Opening 1985-1987 (Box 10)
    - Party 1986 (Box 10)
    - Riverfront Ball 1983 (Box 10)
    - Valentine Ball 1982 (Box 10)
    - VCA Grant 1987 (Box 10)
  - Maymont Foundation 1979-1994
    - Maymont Foundation 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Maymont Foundation 1981 (Box 10)
    - Maymont Foundation 1982 (Box 10)
    - Maymont Foundation 1983 (Box 10)
    - Maymont Foundation 1984 (Box 11)
    - Maymont Foundation 1985 (Box 11)
    - Maymont Foundation 1986 (Box 11)
    - Maymont Foundation 1988 (Box 11)
    - Maymont Foundation 1990 (Box 12)
    - Maymont Foundation 1991 (Box 12)
    - Maymont Foundation 1992 (Box 12)
    - Maymont Foundation 1993 (Box 12)
    - Maymont Foundation 1994 (Box 12)
    - Antiques Article 1983, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Centennial 1993 (Box 13)
    - Centennial Swan Ball 1993 (Box 13)
    - Committee for Visitor Center Planning 1987 (Box 13)
    - Historical Committee 1983-1990 (Box 13)
    - House Benevolent Society 1985 (Box 13)
    - House Benevolent Society 1988 (Box 14)
    - House Benevolent Society 1989 (Box 14)
    - House Benevolent Society 1990 (Box 14)
    - House Benevolent Society Letter 1986 (Box 14)
    - House Benevolent Society Tea 1985 (Box 14)
    - Special Gifts and Bequests Committee 1984 (Box 14)
  - Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce 1981-1992
    - Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce (April-October) 1982 (Box 14)
    - Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce (November-December) 1982 (Box 14)
    - Metropolitan Richmond Chamber of Commerce 1983 (Box 14)
    - Cocktail Party 1983 (Box 14)
    - Dinner (Ellsworth) 1983 (Box 14)
    - Executive Committee 1982 (Box 15)
    - Executive Committee (January-June) 1983 (Box 15)
    - Executive Committee Retreat 1983 (Box 15)
    - Focus on Our Future 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Graphics 1982 (Box 15)
    - Richmond Convention and Visitor's Bureau 1981 (Box 15)
  - Planned Parenthood 1942-1992
    - Planned Parenthood 1942-1963 (Box 16)
    - Planned Parenthood 1979-1983 (Box 16)
    - Planned Parenthood 1984-1987 (Box 16)
    - Planned Parenthood 1988 (Box 16)
    - Planned Parenthood 1990 (Box 16)
    - Planned Parenthood 1991 (Box 17)
    - Planned Parenthood 1992 (Box 17)
    - 50th Anniversary Style Article 1990-1991 (Box 17)
    - Abortion article in Style--Replies and Comments 1990 (Box 17)
    - Abortion War[ Richmond Times-Dispatch] 1992 (Box 17)
    - Appeals 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Gift of Life 1951 (Box 17)
    - Mackenzie, Ross 1990 (Box 17)
    - Public Affairs 1980 (Box 18)
    - Vaughn, Jack Hood 1975 (Box 18)
    - Wattleton, Faye 1985, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Richmond Better Housing Coalition (RBHC) 1984-1994
    - Abandon Property Project n.d. 1989, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Advisory Council for Affordable Housing and Community Development (Box 18)
    - All Saints Episcopal Church 1992 (Box 18)
    - Applications for HUD Grant, Warner and Bliley correspondence (Box 18)
    - Assembly on Housing in Virginia (Box 18)
    - Basic Organization Materials-Goals, Committees (Box 18)
    - Board of Director's Meetings n.d. 1988-1989 (Box 18)
    - Board of Director's Meetings 1990-1991 (Box 18)
    - Board of Director's Meetings n.d. (1 of 2) 1992-1993 (Box 18)
    - Board of Director's Meetings n.d. (2 of 2) 1992-1993 (Box 18)
    - Board of Director's Meeting 1-26-1994 (Box 19)
    - Brochure and Coalition Purpose (Box 19)
    - Chattanooga Neighborhoods Enterprise, trip 1991 (Box 19)
    - Clarke, Kenneth (Box 19)
    - Cohn, David S.--Low Income Tax Credits 1988 (Box 19)
    - Community Awareness and Public Policy Task Force 1988 (Box 19)
    - Coordinating Committee Meeting, March 30, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Daily Planet (Box 19)
    - Daily Planet (Street People Center) 1989 (Box 19)
    - Daily Planet 1990 (Box 19)
    - Dept. of Housing and Community Development, Housing Issues in VA: A Report1987 (Box 19)
    - Ecumenical Housing Conference, Sept. 1989 (Box 19)
    - Executive Committee Meetings 1988-1990 (Box 19)
    - Executive Committee Meetings 1991-1992 (Box 19)
    - Executive Committee Meetings 1993 (Box 19)
    - Executive Committee Meetings 1994 (Box 19)
    - Executive Director Search (Box 20)